Hi, I'm Jacob Hammond Product Designer



About

I am a creative, fast thinking and passionate individual who loves to design user centric products and experiences. My skills span user research and testing, interaction design, visual design, design systems, production and front-end development.

Contact

07504986960 contact@jacobhammond.co.uk London, UK

Values

Collaborative
Inclusive
Pragmatic
Empathetic

Skills

User journeys
Wireframing
Information architechture
Interaction design
Visual design
Design systems
Prototyping (low-fi & hi-fi)
Video editing and production
Graphic Design
Photography
Facilitation

Tools I use

through discovery, exploration, concept and validation

Sharpies & Post-Its
Sketch + Plugins
Adobe CC (inc. After Effects)
Principle, Invision, Marvel
Sublime Text, Atom, CodePen
Git + Github, Bitbucket
Zeplin
Jira, Basecamp
Keynote
DSLR Camera

Experience

Product Designer • Tandem, Feb 2015 - Present

Tandem is on a mission to build a new kind of bank; one that always puts the customer first. As the first full-time designer hired by Tandem, I contributed to building and defining a new brand, facilitated discovery and research sessions to help inform product strategy and direction, challenged business decisions to champion customer experience and designed, delivered and iterated its first websites, native mobile apps and responsive web apps.

- Journey, interaction and visual design for iOS, Android and Web Apps including complex banking flows
- Designed and built prototypes used for testing, generating further investment and creating a unified vision for the product
- Worked closely with product managers and engineers to create a process that aids fast delivery whilst maintaining high standards
- Played major role in defining growth and aquisition strategy and how
 Tandem positions itself as a brand
- Advocated a customer centric and product led approach across the company - ensuring focus was on delivering for our target segment
- Helped define design team principles, guidelines and ways of working
- Engaged in driving a company culture driven by brand values
- Contributed to interviewing and hiring design team members

Co-Founder / Designer • Precise Pixels, May 2011 - Present

Precise Pixels is a team of dedicated, award-winning creative designers and developers. We are passionate about helping ambitious companies and individuals create new digital products and services. Projects include a website for an arts charity, a student housing app, a nightlife app and recently a new kind of bill splitting app.

- Design apps and websites from concept stage to full visual design and prototyping
- Develop fully responsive websites using latest web technologies
- Manage client relationships and project managment

Front-End development

HTML5
CSS3 & Pre-processors
Font-End Frameworks
JS, JQuery, Angular
Gulp, Grunt, Bower
Jekyll

A bit more about me

With experience in both agency and FinTech startups and large companies, I like to apply my skills to solving problems for both users and businesses.

My experience and understanding of development makes it natural for me to communicate and work closely with developers and i'm most comfortable working in crossfunctional agile teams.

Interests and hobbies

I like being part of the design community in London and attending large conferences, job fairs and smaller product talks and hackathons.

Rock & Metal is my favourite kind of music and I often attend gigs or festivals to hear my favourite bands.

Finally, my other passion is food. I love to cook, recently getting into meat smoking and curing, and dream of one day making a living from feeding people.

Find me around

linkedin.com/in/jacobh1992

twitter.com/jacobh1992

instagram.com/jacobh_1992/

UX & UI Deisgner • Fuerte International, June 2014 - Feb 2015

Fuerte International was a startup mobile design agency. I spent 7 months onsite with Dixons Carphone designing their award-winning in-store customer facing 'PinPoint' app - later white-labelled and reskinned and sold to Apple and Samsung stores across Europe and Canada. The rest of my time was spent on other client and agency projects or pitching new ideas to clients.

- Work with designers, developers and project managers to deliver and maintain entire cross-platform apps to tight deadlines
- Design entire apps and iterate the designs appropriately including interaction design, prototypes and creation of assets
- Contribute to and manage web design and development projects
- Deliver specifications to and collaborate with 50+ remote developers

Design & Production Intern • Disney Interactive, July 2012 - July 2013

I worked with the content producers and the lead designer to maintain, update and create content for Disney.co.uk and all websites that branch from it. The websites included, Disney Channel, Disney XD, Disney Junior, Superbia, Club Penguin and all the other websites under the Disney.co.uk domain.

- Design and develop from scratch non commercial web pages for Disney.co.uk and commercial pages for Disney's Ad-Sales team, including Bafta Kids, Madagascar 3 and Mickey's Rockin' Roadshow.
- Complete asset requests and create content for producers that adhered to a range of Disney's strict brand and legal guidelines
- Use many types of software and content management systems such as Disney's in-house Producer Tool Kit to maintain, update and improve Disney websites
- Use video editting and encoding software to eidt, organise and upload
 Disney video clips to Disney websites and external websites

Web Designer • People United, Feb 2011 - May 2012

...more experience history available on my LinkedIn profile

Education

University of Kent • BSc Multimedia Technology & Design with year in industry, Sep 2010 - July 2014

First Class Honours

Scholarship of Academic Excellence 2010

Sagittarius Digital Prize for 'Best Integrated Multimedia Project in Multimedia Technology and Design' 2014

Long Road Sixth Form College • AS / A Levels, Sep 2008 - June 2010 ICT, Design & Technology, History, Maths, Biology, Extended Project, General Studies

Parkside Community College • GCSEs, Sep 2003 - June 2008 14 GCSEs A-C